Let's check the format for our
respondent data, also sometimes
called our people data.
This data may take the form of a
tab in a Google Sheet, like the
one on the screen, or it may be in
a CSV file.
In either case, the format is the
same.
First off, there should be a
column corresponding to a unique
ID for all of the people who have
responded.
So you'll see this is in column A
We have unique IDs for the 100
people who have responded and
shown interest in our democratic
lottery Next there should be a
series of columns that correspond
to our targets So these are the
columns shown in red We've got
gender, age bucket, ethnicity and
disability You need to check that
these correspond to your target
data listed under the category
column of your target data.
So here again, we have gender, age
bucket, ethnicity, disability,
exactly the same as in our
respondent data.
Now, there may be some other
columns.
For instance, you may need to know
the person's name and their
details for contacting them.
But those columns do not directly
affect how we run our selection.
The key columns for us are the
ones that we're going to use for
targets.
So now take, for example, the
gender column.
The entries in the gender column
must correspond exactly to the
name values listed in your target
data.
So here, under gender, our
possible values are female, male,
non -binary, or other.
And you'll see in the respondents
data, under the gender heading,
All of the entries are either
female, male or non -binary or
other Let's check another one If
we look at age bucket and we move
across to our target data You'll
see that there are various ranges
that are allowed 0 to 17, 18 to 24
and so on If we check back in our
respondents data You'll see that
all of these entries correspond to
those listed in that category.
And the same for all of our target
columns.